“Eat, Mawusi. Food will always comfort you when everything else is lost.”
I thought of my mother. I missed her. I don’t think I had ever missed her that badly before.
I felt so lonely. It is strange to feel so alone surrounded by a crowd,
But big cities have that strange quality: the larger they are, the smaller you feel. They make you feel like you don’t matter.
“Eat, my sweet. Eat, and you’ll feel better.”
I looked around. In the absence of trees, I was not really spoiled for choice,
But now was not the time to be picky, I was hungry, so anything would do.
I saw a tiny white worm climbing on a statue and I gulped it.
“Ugh!” I heard voices behind me. “Dear me, those migrants are disgusting.”
I turned around.
“What do you mean?” I asked, my mouth still full,
“And they have no manners.”
One plump grey pigeon was addressing two smaller ones, ignoring me completely.
“Don’t you miss the good old days where we could feel at home here, having a peaceful luncheon undisturbed? This scene just spoiled my appetite.”
“Sorry”, I said, “I’m new here.”
“Obviously”, he sneered.
“If you don’t eat worms, what do you eat, then?” I asked.
“Bread, of course”, he replied haughtily. “We are civilised creatures.
But I suppose there is no bread in your little jungle. No wonder you have to fall back on hunting smelly insects. How degrading.”
“Don’t be rude, Archie”, said one of the smaller pigeons.
“She probably doesn’t understand us. Dooo yoouu haaave breaaad in aaa friii caaa?”
“I’m not stupid”, I said, “and of course I know bread. But that’s what humans eat. We just prefer fresh food. Fresh food.”
They all laughed, mimicking me.
“I don’t know why you dislike them, Rosie”, added the first pigeon. “I find those migrants amusing.
But let’s head back to the Ritz, shall we? They may have disposed of the afternoon tea’s scones by now.”
And they left me there, alone in the crowd, feeling stupid with the leftovers of my first English meal.